- [Trainer] Okay, so now, let's get started
on working on the form to add new players.
We'll first work on the HTML
and then we're going to be working
on the functions to add new players.
Okay, so the first thing I want
to do is go in player list.
'cause I realize in between videos
that there was a little typo
that was preventing the application from running.
And it's in the PlayerList.jsx.
This is not a dot, this item, but this,item.
And if you save this and then you go into the application,
now, you're going to be able to see this here.
So you're going to be able to see the players
that we added to the database, the menu at the top,
and then the phone, the strength,
the email, team, and so on and so forth.
So this is what you should be seeing
once you make that correction.
Okay, so let's go back to our form here,
and we're going to start adding some HTML here.
So what I'm going to do is transform this
into a class component.
All right, so what I'm going to do here is basically
you raised all this, just to make it simpler,
I'm going to first import React from React.
I'm also going to import axios
'cause we're going to be using Axios
in this particular component.
And we're going to be working on some of the stuff
after in the next video related to Axios.
So PlayerForm extends React.Component,
and then we're going to render and then return.
And then we're going to start doing the HTML for the form.
Okay. So the first thing we need,
as with anything that we've done
in this particular project,
is a div with a className of row, like so.
And then inside of that row,
we're going to do a title with a class name
of center to center, add a new player, okay?
Then we're going to start the form.
So we start a form with a class name of column s12,
which means that we're going to maximize
the width of that particular row.
Then we're going to create a new row.
And inside of that row, we're going to have our first input.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So we're going to repeat a lot of the same things.
So whatever we do in this row,
we're going to be copying and pasting again.
All right, so the first thing we need in that row
is a div with a class name of input field
with half of this particular row.
And then this input field will have an input
with the ID of first name.
And we're going to use ref of first name.
Now, when you run the application, the ref,
and leverage the ref for getting the input from that
and then sending it to the database.
You may have some documentation on that.
I know there's a new methods that are being used for that.
You can read on that and update your own application
with that particular reference.
This is still relevant for React,
but there's new methods that you can use as well.
So feel free to read on that and go ahead,
and use whatever makes sense for you.
Text, and then we're going to have a label, htmlFor,
firstName, and the label's going to be First Name.
Okay, so now, what we're going to do is copy all this here,
including that input feel.
We're going to do it one more time.
For this, we're going to change all the references
to the first name to last name,
and FYI, if you're not familiar with what I just did,
so I did Option + Click to select several items
at the same time, and then we're going
to change the label to Last Name.
Okay. Now, what we're going to do is do the exact same thing
one more time, but we're going to copy a new row
because if you look at it here, we're doing half
of that row for the first name and half for the last name.
So the next row will have two more fields
using half the width of that row.
So that's basically what we're going to do.
So we're going to copy from line 10 to line 19, like so,
and insert it below, like so.
And now, we have a new row with two fields that are going
to take half the span of that particular row.
So for these ones, all we have to do is click,
Option + Click.
If you're using VS code, that's basically what I'm doing.
Option + Click on a Mac,
and we're going to switch this to phone
and then change the level as well to phone, like so.
And then we're going to do the same thing here
for the last input field, click, Option + Click,
Option + Click, and switch this to email.
And also change the label to email, like so.
And then finally, just below that div,
we're going to add the button to add the player.
So we're going to create a button with a class name of btn.
These are all, again, materialized classes, waves, light,
and we're going to be of type of submit,
name, action, and then Add player.
Okay. So let's save this.
And if you go back to here,
you should see the player form.
Let's refresh this. There you go.
So we see now the player form.
We can't really act on it
because right now, we don't have a function
that executes whenever we click on the button yet,
but we're going to do that in the next video.